Jamie Allen

Senior Front-End Developer

191 Grant Avenue Hamilton, ON, L8N 2X9 (905) 962-6212 jamie@llen.ca eimaj.net

What I'm looking for...

I thrive in a creative environment. Working closely with designers, developers and clients I strive to make every project as accessible and intuitive as possible for the end user. My main focus is front end development, user experience and design. I also have an interest in APIs, processes and web servers.

Qualifications

- Javascript (ES6, Coffeescript, jQuery)
- Node and Yarn, React and Redux, Webpack
- HTML5, <u>CSS3 (Sass)</u>
- Git
- Ruby and Rails
- Sketch, Invision, Photoshop, Illustrator
- Ubuntu servers, Nginx, Digital Ocean, Firebase, Heroku

Experience

factor[e] design initiative, Hamilton - Senior User Experience Specialist May 2009 - Present

Work closely with clients, designers and developers to build the best possible solution to meet the needs of the application. Every project is custom and designed to achieve the goals of the client.

- Shifted: Marketing Website (getshifted.ca)
- Laura Tedesco Jewellery Design (<u>lauratedesco.com</u>)
- Brux House Restaurant (bruxhouse.com)
- McMaster Student Union (msumcmaster.ca)
- Expressing Vibrancy Research Project (<u>expressingvibrancy.ca</u>)

Social Media Group, Hamilton - Social Media Analyst

May 2008 - May 2009

In house web project development, programming and design.

Education

George Brown College - Design Management

September 2007 - April 2008

University of Guelph - Bachelor of Arts with Honours - Fine Art

September 2000 - April 2005

Interests

In the last year I was an organizer for the Embrace UX conference (embraceux.com) in Hamilton, I've mentored for Ladies Learning Code in Hamilton and I have volunteered for local political issues like public transit and various elections.

Currently most of my spare time is been spent with my family. I also enjoy painting (society6.com/eimaj), design (eimaj.net/pixel.html), strumming guitars, gardening and sailing when I can find the time.

Social

Github

github.com/eimaj/

LinkedIn

ca.linkedin.com/in/eimaj

Twitter

twitter.com/eimaj

Instagram

instagram.com/eimaj